<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Henrique Dias</title>
    <link>https://henriquedias.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Henrique Dias</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:05:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://henriquedias.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>3 things I would like to be</title>
      <link>https://henriquedias.com/personal/3-things-i-would-like-to-be</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henriquedias.com/personal/3-things-i-would-like-to-be</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following me through the past time,  you probably know I want to go further in technology field (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/about/&#34;&gt;about page&lt;/a&gt;). But it is not the unique thing I would like to be because there are 3 things I would like to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we choose to be something or to follow some field of study, we should think a lot about it to find out if we are sure we want to follow it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to follow the technology field. I know it&amp;rsquo;s not late to change, but I really like that.  But where&amp;rsquo;s the fun of being just &lt;strong&gt;ONE&lt;/strong&gt; thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two more things that fascinates me and I want to share it with you. So, &lt;strong&gt;the 3 things I would like to be are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software Engineer;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writer;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photographer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know that those three things does not have a lot in common. But I like them. So now I&amp;rsquo;m going to answer the three big questions: &lt;strong&gt;why do you want to be &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-you-want-to-be-software-engineer:1bac5a5f6397a0426092ef090a968e02&#34;&gt;Why do you want to be Software Engineer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/images/technology-solutions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Finding solutions.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like technology since I was a little child. It always fascinated me. Technology is a way to &lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; things, to &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; things, to &lt;strong&gt;help&lt;/strong&gt; people in a big number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With technology we can do a lot of things we couldn&amp;rsquo;t ever imagine it was possible: help the older woman crossing the zebra crossing with more security; helping that little kids of Africa giving them food faster; a lot of etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_engineer&#34;&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/a&gt; to, mainly, help people finding technological solutions to its problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-you-want-to-be-writer:1bac5a5f6397a0426092ef090a968e02&#34;&gt;Why do you want to be Writer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/images/writing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Writing... it appears to be amazing.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writer&#34;&gt;writer&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing thing, it isn&amp;rsquo;t? It appears to be. A writer could &lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; his own stories, &lt;strong&gt;make&lt;/strong&gt; his own worlds, &lt;strong&gt;build&lt;/strong&gt; his own characters, &lt;strong&gt;shape&lt;/strong&gt; his own society, &lt;strong&gt;develop&lt;/strong&gt; his own system and&amp;hellip; an infinity of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That infinity of possibilities is what attracts me more. The ability to create, to shape, to develop, to make. Of course there is nothing in the way that stops me to write stories&amp;hellip; so &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s a possibility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-you-want-to-be-photographer:1bac5a5f6397a0426092ef090a968e02&#34;&gt;Why do you want to be Photographer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/images/mosteiro_jeronimos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jerónimos Monastery. Taken by me.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photographs are simply amazing things. They record a moment of our lives (or not): something which happens in a determined space-time. They simply record it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when we take a good &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photographer&#34;&gt;photograph&lt;/a&gt; is like taking that moment to the eternity. It will always be saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as writing, there is nothing in the way that stops me, so I will continue taking photos and improving my capacity of doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this post about 3 things I would like to be. If you liked it, you may share it :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the technology a good or a bad thing?</title>
      <link>https://henriquedias.com/personal/technology-good-bad</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 12:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henriquedias.com/personal/technology-good-bad</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk a little bit about technology and if it is a good or a bad thing. This article is, of course, according to my point of view. The main question, for now, is &amp;ldquo;is the technology a good or a bad thing?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-technology:e2967cca0b7243df17bf66bb689a5d12&#34;&gt;What is technology?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what is technology? I think it is a difficult word to define but according to the dictionary, technology is the science whose objective is the application of technical and scientific knowledge for industrial and commercial purposes so technology isn’t only the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/images/wheel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is technology&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        This is technology
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Almost everything we use everyday is technology or made using it. The small piece of paper you wrote in last minute, was made with technology. Technology can be useful to the humankind. There are a lot of examples: the cars we use to travel, the cooker we use to make food, the phones we use to call each other, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-is-it-always-good:e2967cca0b7243df17bf66bb689a5d12&#34;&gt;But is it always good?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people would say yes, other slice of people would say no. The reality, in my point of view, is that (almost) everything which can be used for good things can also be used for bad things. I give you an example: apparently, your smartphone is harmless. But, and if a person, who was present in the factory of the brand of your smartphone when it was made, were with her soul corrupted and implanted a small bomb on each smartphone? What is known today, this example never had a real case, but it already happened with other type of devices.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/images/nucbomb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Technology may cause disasters&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Technology may cause disasters
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The real problem here is not if the technology has more advantages or disadvantages. Is not if the technology can be used most for bad or for good. The real problem here is people. I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain you why. People are made of feelings. People are who create technology. Feelings can be good or bad. If the feelings of a person can be good or bad, the technology this person creates can be also good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has its own dark side and its light side. Normally, what should happen is having both sides balanced. But there&amp;rsquo;s some people who don&amp;rsquo;t have. The people who have their dark side unbalanced can be very, very, very dangerous. They’re people with problems, of course.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://henriquedias.com/images/dices.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The choice is yours. Alea jacta est.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        The choice is yours. Alea jacta est.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Concluding, what I&amp;rsquo;ve to say is that technology is neither good, nor bad. What make it good or bad is the people. You. &lt;strong&gt;You are what makes technology good or bad because it depends on your uses, on your needs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have moved, again</title>
      <link>https://henriquedias.com/personal/i-have-moved-again</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 22:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henriquedias.com/personal/i-have-moved-again</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have moved, again. From now until the end of the times, &lt;strong&gt;coxpe.com&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;henriquedias.com/blog&lt;/strong&gt; are gone, and &lt;strong&gt;henriquedias.com&lt;/strong&gt; is the unified version of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perfection is achieved, not when there is nothing more to add, but when there is nothing left to take away.&amp;rdquo; - Antoine de Saint-Exupéry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote above tells the &lt;strong&gt;main reason&lt;/strong&gt; I have made this change. The content created by me was dispersed on the web so I moved it all to one place. I &lt;strong&gt;took away&lt;/strong&gt; some things, trying to achieve the perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have a lot of things, dispersed. One thing, one place, is better. Everything is concentrated. Everything is here. There is nothing left to take away, but there is something more to add.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason was that COXPE was receiving a small amount of visits a month and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to maintain two domains with few content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m studying I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of time to write new posts, much less to two websites. I&amp;rsquo;ve also &lt;a href=&#34;http://pplware.com&#34;&gt;Pplware&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://kids.pplware.com&#34;&gt;Pplware Kids&lt;/a&gt; to write for. So, unifying this two blogs was the best choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-are-using-the-default-theme:1e104a160fedfaeafcd9438459ab567c&#34;&gt;You are using the default theme&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, and regardly to the new design of this blog: I&amp;rsquo;m using the WordPress default theme. Why? There are some reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme is &lt;strong&gt;clean, simple, beautiful&lt;/strong&gt; and almost &lt;strong&gt;perfect&lt;/strong&gt;. It provides a clean design to read. There are advantages for me and for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; think about this change? Do you like it? Or not?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>